### SANTHIYA SUGUMAR

Software Developer

https://www.linkedin.com/in/santhiyasugumar

santhiyasugumar22@gmail.com

+917339663947

Full stack developer with totally three + years of experience in developing back-end and front-end features for global companies. My goal is to be an innovative Software Engineer, specializing in the field of front end and back end. I am committed to continuous learning and advancing current software engineering practices.

# **Work Experience**

### Logic Research Labs, April 2019 ~ Present

Software Developer



Gathering requirements from client/Business team and estimation. Worked on full Stack web developer, working with the latest frameworks and API

### STS, Jan 2017 ~ June 2018

**Program Analyst** 

Responsible for application code and designing. Responsive for database and front end design.



# **Technology Stack**











3 CSS







B Bootstrap PostgreSQL © C# Codelgniter JS Javascript

## **Education**

SASTRA UNIVERSITY 2012 - 2016

Bachelor of Technology - Computer Science and Engineering (71%)

St. Joseph's Girls Hr. Sec. School 2012

HSC - Higher Secondary Certificate (88%)

St. Joseph's Girls Hr. Sec. School 2010

SSLC - Secondary School Leaving Certificate (93%)

## **Project Experience**

#### **CDAC**

https://www.cdac.org.sg/en/



CDAC is a non-profit self-help group for the Chinese community having various supporting scheme. Big architectural application with configurable RBAC

Frontend: Bootstrap 4 , jQuery Backend: Slim framework Database: posgreSQL

API: SendGrid

Role: Designer, Developer

#### Nubesol

https://nubesol.co.in/



Mobile app transforming the Sugar industry ecosystem.

Frontend and Backend: Zoho Creator, Deluge Script

API: Google Map

Role: Designer, Developer

## **GradsKey**

https://www.gradskey.com



Social Network for Students, Professionals & Academicians Progressive Web App (PWA) with push notification enabled.

Frontend: Bootstrap 4 , jQuery Backend: Codelgniter 3 Database: PosgreSQL

API: SendGrid Role: Developer

## **Micro Finance ERP System**

Microfinance provides end-to-end software solutions for microfinance institutions. It support optimize Multilingual keyboards.

Frontend: Bootstrap 3, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Backend: Slim framework

Database: MySQL API: Bulk SMS API Role: Developer

## **Achievements**

- ✓ Secured First prize in Natural Language Processing, SASTRA University-SRC, Nov 2014.
- ✓ Secured Third prize in Mathematics-4, SASTRA University-SRC Examination, May 2014.

# Languages

- ✓ English
- ✓ Tamil Native or Bilingual

#### Declaration

I hereby declare that all the above details and particulars furnished by me are true to the best of knowledge.